Inventory of the Mark Slobin Papers, 1947 - 2013
Mark Slobin Papers1947 - 2013
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Mark Slobin
2015-09
12
14
Mark Slobin is the Winslow-Kaplan Professor of Music at Wesleyan University.
The Mark Slobin Papers contain materials pertaining to his "American Cantorate" project, media coverage of Jewish ethnomusicology, as well as assorted personal papers. The collection consists of 14 Paige boxes and Holliger boxes, primarily containing correspondence and letters, newspaper clippings, interview responses, personal items, U-matic tape recordings, photographs, musical scores, and both published and unpublished writings of Slobin and others. This collection is unprocessed.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Donated by Mark Slobin, 2015.
Biographical Note
Mark Slobin is the Winslow-Kaplan Professor of Music at Wesleyan University.
Collection Overview
The Mark Slobin Papers contain materials pertaining to his "American Cantorate" project, media coverage of Jewish ethnomusicology, as well as assorted personal papers. The collection consists of 14 Paige and Holliger boxes, primarily containing correspondence and letters, newspaper clippings, interview responses, personal items, U-matic tape recordings, photographs, musical scores, and both published and unpublished writings of Slobin and others. This collection consists of two accessions, 2015-09 and 2015-26, and is unprocessed.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Slobin, Mark; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Music Dept.; Cantors (Judaism).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I. American Cantorate
  - The Jewish Week articles, folder (Box 1)
  - Cerini, folder (Box 1)
  - Nicki Axe, folder (Box 1)
  - Cantor Mimi Frishman, folder (Box 1)
  - Moldawsky, folder (Box 1)
  - From Zimmerman archive, folder (Box 1)
  - Weintshl poem, folder (Box 1)
  - Klepper, folder (Box 1)
  - Rosenblatt discography, folder (Box 1)
  - Individual careers, folder (Box 1)
  - Scherr, Freedman, folder (Box 1)
  - Smolover, folder (Box 1)
  - Roochvarg, Chomsky, Stein, folder (Box 1)
  - Katzew, folder (Box 1)
  - Assorted Jewish, folder (Box 1)
  - Paul Zim, folder (Box 1)
  - Seixas correspondence, folder (Box 1)
  - Katchko talk, folder (Box 1)
  - Forverts, folder (Box 1)
  - Misc. 19th c., folder (Box 1)
  - Occident, folder (Box 1)
  - Cong. histories, folder (Box 1)
  - Karp typology, folder (Box 1)
  - Misc. article on history, folder (Box 1)
  - Yiddish writing translation, folder (Box 1)
  - Misc. reform, folder (Box 1)
  - Organizations, statements, folder (Box 1)
  - Women clippings, folder (Box 1)
  - Cantor clippings, folder (Box 1)
  - Misc. notes, folder (Box 1)
  - Europe, folder (Box 1)
  - Non-Jewish compar., folder (Box 1)
  - J. Litwig Music Conference, folder, 1947, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Karp, A Century of Conservative Judaism in the United States, folder (Box 1)
  - Rosenbaum, folder, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Voices of Israel scrapbook, folder, 1952 (Box 1)
  - CA convention, folder, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Detroit cantorial, folder (Box 1)
  - Shames talk, folder (Box 1)
  - S tape analysis 2 - sung samples, folder (Box 2)
  - Rabbi survery responses, folder (Box 2)
  - Synagogue questionnaire responses, folder (Box 2)
  - Tape transcripts, folder (Box 2)
  - Core sung sample follow-up survey, folder (Box 2)
  - Cantorate, folder, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Cantorate correspondence and memos, folder, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Cantors Assembly questionnaire, folder (Box 3)
  - Misc. interview notes, folder (Box 3)
  - Taped interview transcripts, folder (Box 3)
  - Lay leadership questionnaire, folder (Box 3)
  - Cantor notes and quotes, folder (Box 3)
  - Questionnaire ACC, folder (Box 3)
  - Lionel Wolberger's transcriptions, folder (Box 4)
  - Ethnic Heritage #7, U-matic tape, 10/1982 (Box 4)
  - Music in Middletown, U-matic tape (Box 4)
  - Applebaum Affair, U-matic tape (Box 4)
  - Misc. papers, folder (Box 4)
  - Saul Meisels correspondence, folder (Box 4)
  - Draft material, folder (Box 4)
  - Waivers, folder (Box 4)
  - Frigyesi report, folder (Box 4)
  - Puran report, folder (Box 4)
  - Lecha Dodi responses, folder (Box 4)
  - Stats from questionnaires, folder (Box 4)
  - L.A. Sephardic, folder (Box 4)
  - Lionel Wolfberger's Survey of Conservative Services, folder (Box 4)
  - Bios of participants in sung sample collection, folder (Box 4)
  - Misc. journal, folder (Box 4)
  - Borchu report, folder (Box 4)
  - Transcripts of sung sample #3, folder (Box 4)
- Series II. Papers
  - Contracts, folder (Box 5)
  - Misc. projects, folder (Box 5)
  - Documents, photos, folder (Box 5)
  - Event participation, folder (Box 5)
  - Music at Wesleyan, folder, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Worlds of Music, folder, 1984- (Box 5)
  - Conference at Wesleyan, folder, 2006 (Box 5)
  - Conference organized by Mark Slobin at Yale, folder, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Jerusalem Congress, folder, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Sound systems, folder (Box 5)
  - CUNY conference, folder, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Studying the Yiddish Folksong, folder (Box 5)
  - Permissions, folder (Box 5)
  - Misc. letters and articles, folder (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan, folder (Box 5)
  - Assorted library cards, cards (Box 5)
  - Jewish Ethnic Music Festival, folder, 1981 (Box 5)
  - The Society for Ethnomusicology Honorary Membership, folder, 2013 (Box 5)
  - Modern Language Association of America award, folder (Box 5)
  - First conference paper/American Musicology Society, folder, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Slobin art, folder (Box 5)
  - Misc. documents, folder (Box 6)
  - Hungarian conference, folder, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Beregovski chronology, folder (Box 6)
  - Jewish film music talk, folder (Box 6)
  - Klezmer interviews, folder (Box 6)
  - Beregovski/Old Jewish folk music, folder, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Bereg Klezmer CD, folder (Box 6)
  - Society for Ethnomusicology, folder (Box 6)
  - Aspects on Music and Multiculturalism, report, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Yiddish folksong from the Ruth Rubin archive, folder (Box 6)
  - IREX conference, folder, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Micromusics, folder (Box 6)
  - ACLS, folder (Box 6)
  - Harvard conference, folder, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Moscow conference, folder, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Play produced at Wesleyan, David's Violin, folder, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Materials for Kirghiz Instrumental Music, folder, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Studying the American Musical Experience, folder, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Shulamis project, folder (Box 6)
  - Klezmer talks and materials, folder (Box 6)
  - VFPA book, folder (Box 6)
  - Assorted Wesleyan and Public Life materials, folder (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan diplomas, diploma (Box 6)
  - Wesleyan University diploma, diploma (Box 6)
  - IREX, folder, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
  - Wenner-Gren, folder (Box 7)
  - US-Soviet Music Commission, folder, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Mariam Nirenberg album project, folder (Box 7)
  - Plates and figures for music in the cultue of northern Afghanistan, folder, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Cantor permissions, folder (Box 8)
  - CCA, folder (Box 8)
  - Misc. correspondence, folder (Box 8)
  - S tape analysis 1, folder (Box 8)
  - Cantorate website, folder (Box 8)
  - Frigyesi report copy, folder (Box 8)
  - Cantors' project, folder (Box 8)
  - Cantor, folder (Box 8)
  - Kirgiz Instrumental Music - Slobin Masters Thesis, bound, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Instrumental Music in Northern Afghanistan - Slobin Doctoral Thesis, bound, 1969 (Box 9)
  - The Wesleyan Song Book, bound, 1922 (Box 9)
  - Collection of music notes and drafts, folder (Box 10)
  - Untitled media disk (4), folder (Box 11)
  - Untitled U-matic tape, folder (Box 11)
  - Music of Northern Afghanistan empty tape case, folder (Box 12)
  - Slobin - outakes empty tape case, folder (Box 12)
  - Afghan photos, notes, and clippings, folder (Box 13)
  - Slobin's ASCAP-DEEMS TAYLOR Award, plaque, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Slobin's ASCAP-DEEMS TAYLOR Award, plaque, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Untitled collection of photo slides (3), folder (Box 14)